<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Oscar López</title><link>https://oscarlp6.dev/en/</link><description>Recent content on Oscar López</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>es-mx</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://oscarlp6.dev/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>🕒 Task vs Promise: Chaining</title><link>https://oscarlp6.dev/en/blogs/task-vs-promises/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://oscarlp6.dev/en/blogs/task-vs-promises/</guid><description>The first language in which I learned to work asynchronously was JavaScript. Initially, it was very challenging because it was a completely different way of thinking from what I had learned in university. Once I internalized the principles of asynchronous programming, it became much easier. So, when I started working in C#, I immediately noticed the similarities between Task and Promise since they are practically equivalent.
But when trying to chain promises the same way as in JavaScript, I encountered a peculiarity.</description></item><item><title>🛠️ Branded Types</title><link>https://oscarlp6.dev/en/blogs/branded-types/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://oscarlp6.dev/en/blogs/branded-types/</guid><description>As a developer, exploring and understanding Branded Types in TypeScript has been a revelation to me. Before delving into this topic, let me share a brief personal experience on how I have evolved in my perception of working under pressure, something that in many ways reflects my approach to complex concepts like Branded Types.
I remember when taking pride in working under pressure was almost a badge of honor on my resume.</description></item><item><title>📊 Obsidian: Nutrition</title><link>https://oscarlp6.dev/en/blogs/nutrition-system-obsidian/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://oscarlp6.dev/en/blogs/nutrition-system-obsidian/</guid><description>Although I am not a fitness enthusiast, this year I have committed to improving my health. This has led me to pay much more attention to the nutritional information of my meals and to have greater control over my daily intake. However, like any developer, I don&amp;rsquo;t want to spend too much time consistently doing these tasks. Therefore, I have developed a system that allows me to track my meals throughout the day in conjunction with my journal.</description></item><item><title>🚀 Obsidian: Projects</title><link>https://oscarlp6.dev/en/blogs/projects-obsidian/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://oscarlp6.dev/en/blogs/projects-obsidian/</guid><description>Recently, I shared how I manage my knowledge base, and I promised to share the systems I use to organize and record information about my goals and projects, both in software and other disciplines.
This time, I want to delve into how I structure and advance in my projects, managing the tasks to be performed and those that arise along the way. As a developer, but also as an individual committed to achieving goals in various areas of my life, I have devised a system that allows me to maintain control and a global vision of each project, from its conception to its completion.</description></item><item><title>Obsidian: Knowledge base</title><link>https://oscarlp6.dev/en/blogs/obsidian-knowledge-organization/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://oscarlp6.dev/en/blogs/obsidian-knowledge-organization/</guid><description>🗄️ Obsidian: Knowledge Organization A couple of days ago, I shared the tool I use to manage all my knowledge base, and I had promised to share the systems I use to organize and record knowledge and information about my habits.
This time I want to share how I organize my notes and the things I learn. Personally, I am a software developer, so I have a specific space for the knowledge and resources I gather about technologies that interest me, and since that&amp;rsquo;s my most &amp;ldquo;nourished&amp;rdquo; space, it will be the one I use as an example.</description></item><item><title>Obsidian Introduction</title><link>https://oscarlp6.dev/en/blogs/obsidian-introduction/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://oscarlp6.dev/en/blogs/obsidian-introduction/</guid><description>🚀 My Personal Productivity System For some time now, I&amp;rsquo;ve been using what&amp;rsquo;s now known as journaling. It&amp;rsquo;s always been a form of personal catharsis for me, where I document my emotions, concerns, and feelings. However, lately, it has evolved, thanks to tools like Obsidian, into what many might call a &amp;ldquo;second brain.&amp;rdquo; Even before, Obsidian was defined as such, a tool for your second brain. Though I&amp;rsquo;m not fond of the term, it&amp;rsquo;s a fact that it&amp;rsquo;s an extremely powerful tool.</description></item><item><title>The Reader Monad in Action 📖</title><link>https://oscarlp6.dev/en/blogs/exploring-reader-monad/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2024 19:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://oscarlp6.dev/en/blogs/exploring-reader-monad/</guid><description>📖 My Experience with the Reader Monad I embarked on what seemed like a trivial but profoundly educational side project. My task: to build a tool for managing inventories, sales, and purchases in a store. However, beyond the apparent simplicity of the project, my true purpose lies in delving into two technologies that have captured my attention remarkably: functional programming and Next.js.
🌐 Introduction This project serves as a canvas where I can apply and refine my knowledge in functional programming, a paradigm that offers a unique perspective on tackling software problems.</description></item><item><title>Working Under Pressure 🤯</title><link>https://oscarlp6.dev/en/blogs/working-underpressure/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 17:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://oscarlp6.dev/en/blogs/working-underpressure/</guid><description>🤯 I Don&amp;rsquo;t Like Working Under Pressure As a remote developer in a company with a strong culture, I must admit that over time, I have lost the taste for working under pressure. I remember in my previous job, pressure was the norm, with tight deadlines and projects deviating completely from estimations. A stark contrast to how I handle things now.
In my early days of crafting my resume, I used to take pride in being able to work under pressure, and yes, I am&amp;hellip; well, effective in the sense that I might not do my best work under pressure, but at least I get the tasks done.</description></item><item><title>Building my File Organizer: Part 1</title><link>https://oscarlp6.dev/en/blogs/building-file-organizer-part-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2023 20:25:35 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://oscarlp6.dev/en/blogs/building-file-organizer-part-1/</guid><description>Every day we download and create files, whether it be in Word, Excel, Notepad, etc. And, at least in my case, I always find myself leaving all my downloads in the default folder and all the files I create on the desktop with the promise of someday organizing them in a proper place. Although that day does come, because I like to keep my desktop organized, I think it&amp;rsquo;s a task that I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t have to do myself, but that I can automate.</description></item></channel></rss>