<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>systems on Oscar López</title><link>https://oscarlp6.dev/en/tags/systems/</link><description>Recent content in systems on Oscar López</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>es-mx</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://oscarlp6.dev/en/tags/systems/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>📊 Obsidian: Nutrition</title><link>https://oscarlp6.dev/en/blogs/nutrition-system-obsidian/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://oscarlp6.dev/en/blogs/nutrition-system-obsidian/</guid><description>Although I am not a fitness enthusiast, this year I have committed to improving my health. This has led me to pay much more attention to the nutritional information of my meals and to have greater control over my daily intake. However, like any developer, I don&amp;rsquo;t want to spend too much time consistently doing these tasks. Therefore, I have developed a system that allows me to track my meals throughout the day in conjunction with my journal.</description></item><item><title>🚀 Obsidian: Projects</title><link>https://oscarlp6.dev/en/blogs/projects-obsidian/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://oscarlp6.dev/en/blogs/projects-obsidian/</guid><description>Recently, I shared how I manage my knowledge base, and I promised to share the systems I use to organize and record information about my goals and projects, both in software and other disciplines.
This time, I want to delve into how I structure and advance in my projects, managing the tasks to be performed and those that arise along the way. As a developer, but also as an individual committed to achieving goals in various areas of my life, I have devised a system that allows me to maintain control and a global vision of each project, from its conception to its completion.</description></item><item><title>Obsidian: Knowledge base</title><link>https://oscarlp6.dev/en/blogs/obsidian-knowledge-organization/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://oscarlp6.dev/en/blogs/obsidian-knowledge-organization/</guid><description>🗄️ Obsidian: Knowledge Organization A couple of days ago, I shared the tool I use to manage all my knowledge base, and I had promised to share the systems I use to organize and record knowledge and information about my habits.
This time I want to share how I organize my notes and the things I learn. Personally, I am a software developer, so I have a specific space for the knowledge and resources I gather about technologies that interest me, and since that&amp;rsquo;s my most &amp;ldquo;nourished&amp;rdquo; space, it will be the one I use as an example.</description></item></channel></rss>