<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Obsidian on Oscar López</title><link>https://oscarlp6.dev/en/tags/obsidian/</link><description>Recent content in Obsidian on Oscar López</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://oscarlp6.dev/en/tags/obsidian/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>🍽️ Obsidian: Restaurant's rating</title><link>https://oscarlp6.dev/en/blogs/obsidian-restaurants-rating/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://oscarlp6.dev/en/blogs/obsidian-restaurants-rating/</guid><description>I have a very bad memory, which is why I am so obsessed with having systems that make it easier for me to search for information. Many times, if I don&amp;rsquo;t structure it very well, I won&amp;rsquo;t remember how I saved it and will end up losing it anyway. This is a big part of why I like Obsidian so much as a tool; it allows me to structure things in a way very similar to how I do it mentally, meaning in relationships.</description></item><item><title>🚫 Notion vs Obsidian</title><link>https://oscarlp6.dev/en/blogs/notion-vs-obsidian/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://oscarlp6.dev/en/blogs/notion-vs-obsidian/</guid><description>Before implementing my entire productivity system and journaling in Obsidian, I experimented with several other tools. One of the most notable ones is Notion, an impressive and highly customizable tool. However, today I will explore why I believe it is not the best option for productivity systems or things like a second brain.
💡 Organization of ideas and thoughts Since I was in school, I always had difficulties taking notes because I felt that the way we think is not well aligned with how we often take notes.</description></item><item><title>✍️ Obsidian: Journaling</title><link>https://oscarlp6.dev/en/blogs/obsidian-journaling/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://oscarlp6.dev/en/blogs/obsidian-journaling/</guid><description>Since I was around 14 years old, I have found it very satisfying, relaxing, and therapeutic to keep a journal where I write down all sorts of things that happen to me throughout the day. At first, it was just about making a summary of what had happened during the day: important events, feelings, etc.
Over time, I’ve changed the way and the tools I use for it. At first, I did it in OneNote on a tablet I had when I was 14 years old.</description></item><item><title>📊 Obsidian: Nutrition</title><link>https://oscarlp6.dev/en/blogs/nutrition-system-obsidian/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://oscarlp6.dev/en/blogs/nutrition-system-obsidian/</guid><description>Although I am not a fitness enthusiast, this year I have committed to improving my health. This has led me to pay much more attention to the nutritional information of my meals and to have greater control over my daily intake. However, like any developer, I don&amp;rsquo;t want to spend too much time consistently doing these tasks. Therefore, I have developed a system that allows me to track my meals throughout the day in conjunction with my journal.</description></item><item><title>🚀 Obsidian: Projects</title><link>https://oscarlp6.dev/en/blogs/projects-obsidian/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://oscarlp6.dev/en/blogs/projects-obsidian/</guid><description>Recently, I shared how I manage my knowledge base, and I promised to share the systems I use to organize and record information about my goals and projects, both in software and other disciplines.
This time, I want to delve into how I structure and advance in my projects, managing the tasks to be performed and those that arise along the way. As a developer, but also as an individual committed to achieving goals in various areas of my life, I have devised a system that allows me to maintain control and a global vision of each project, from its conception to its completion.</description></item><item><title>Obsidian: Knowledge base</title><link>https://oscarlp6.dev/en/blogs/obsidian-knowledge-organization/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://oscarlp6.dev/en/blogs/obsidian-knowledge-organization/</guid><description>🗄️ Obsidian: Knowledge Organization A couple of days ago, I shared the tool I use to manage all my knowledge base, and I had promised to share the systems I use to organize and record knowledge and information about my habits.
This time I want to share how I organize my notes and the things I learn. Personally, I am a software developer, so I have a specific space for the knowledge and resources I gather about technologies that interest me, and since that&amp;rsquo;s my most &amp;ldquo;nourished&amp;rdquo; space, it will be the one I use as an example.</description></item><item><title>Obsidian Introduction</title><link>https://oscarlp6.dev/en/blogs/obsidian-introduction/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://oscarlp6.dev/en/blogs/obsidian-introduction/</guid><description>🚀 My Personal Productivity System For some time now, I&amp;rsquo;ve been using what&amp;rsquo;s now known as journaling. It&amp;rsquo;s always been a form of personal catharsis for me, where I document my emotions, concerns, and feelings. However, lately, it has evolved, thanks to tools like Obsidian, into what many might call a &amp;ldquo;second brain.&amp;rdquo; Even before, Obsidian was defined as such, a tool for your second brain. Though I&amp;rsquo;m not fond of the term, it&amp;rsquo;s a fact that it&amp;rsquo;s an extremely powerful tool.</description></item></channel></rss>